POONAM FOJDAR

Flat No. 1008, 10th Floor, Tower-4 Panchsheel Wellington, Crossing Republic

Ghaziabad- 201016

Mobile: +918860444771, +919354601595 email: poonam.fojdar2010@gmail.com

day duties and responsibility.

affiliation of SKS World School Branch 04, GNW.



Job Objective:

Seeking a challenging position as an Academic Coordinator where my skills and knowledge will add value to organization. Substantial experience in education planning and teaching.

Experience Summary

TGT Computer Science cum Academic Coordinator at SKS World School Since April 2022
Responsibilities as TGT Computer Science: Handling Computer class III to VI, Overall
responsibility of computer lab smooth operation. Review of Academic Planner. Taking care of
Examination Department smooth operation.
Responsibilities as Academic Coordinator: Meeting with parents and resolve issue, Handle
Parent query and admissions, Responsibility of school activity, Interschool Competitions and
Olympiad, Teacher Substitution and their timetable, check teacher's dairy, log book and

attendance register, Handle print and digital media, Manage and guide teaching staff for day-to-

- Primary Teacher at SKS World School, GNW (Mar 2018 to Mar 2022)
 Responsibilities: Class teacher of class II, responsible for overall academic planning, management, execution and activity calendar for the Pre-Primary Class I & II. Also, responsible to provide Academic leadership for curriculum and content development. Ensure implementation of Administrative System, Process and Policies. Manage successfully CBSE
- Academic Head/ Branch Head at Haebix Pre School, Crossing Republic (Jan 2016 to Mar 2018)
 Responsibilities: Overall planning, management, execution and review of academic and activity
 calendar for the Pre-Primary Classes. Also, responsible to provide Academic leadership for
 curriculum and content development. Ensure implementation of Administrative System, Process
 and Policies. Active involvement in marketing, advertisement and back-office support.
- Academic Head at Mothers lap Pre School, Crossing Republic (Jan 2015 to Dec 2015)
 Responsibilities: Development & Quality of content in the curriculum. Mentor & Monitor teachers in school. Ensure quality assessment and moderation practices. Assist the Principal in all matters of academic and curriculum framing of the school.
- Academic Coordinator at Mothers lap Pre School, Crossing Republic, (Jan 2014 to Dec 2014)
 Responsibilities: Developing the curriculum, overseeing teaching technique and methodologies

and ensuring student and parents satisfaction with the educational process at the school.

- *Off Role Lecturer*, Computer science (BBA, PGDCA and BCA dept.) in MSJ Govt. College Bharatpur, Rajasthan from 2007 to 2008.
- Computer Teacher at KV Bharatpur, Rajasthan 2006-2007
- *Lecturer*, Computer science (BCA dept.) in Institute of Engineering and Future Technology Agra, U.P. from 2004 to 2006.
- Worked as Faculty and Technical assistant for different software in TSP Centre 2004.

Academic Background

- Pursuing MA Psychology from IGNOU.
- Certified Psychology and counselling Skills from Swayam Foundation in 2022.
- Diploma in Yogic Science from Vivekanand Yog Ashram, NIOS in 2022
- B.Ed from Maharshi Dayanand University, Rohtak (Haryana, India)2011-12
- Post Graduate in M.Sc (IT) from DR.B.R.A University, AGRA (2005)
- Graduated in Computer Science (B.C.A.) from DR. B.R.A. University, AGRA (2003)
- Intermediate in Science from Rajasthan Board (2000)
- Matriculation from Rajasthan Board (1998)

Professional Expertise

- Office Package: Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access, Microsoft PowerPoint
- Student Assessment, Creative lesson Planning, Multicultural Awareness
- Parent Teacher communication, Classroom Management, Guided Reading.
- Friendly with Smart classes and intelligent board.

Extra-Curricular

- Certified Yoga Teachers Training programme
- Certified as Yoga Volunteer by The Yoga Certification Board.
- Achieved second position in Athletic games state level competition in year 2000.
- Worked as volunteer for Institutional events in C-Impact from 2000 to 2003.
- Participated in Seminar on Network and security issues in year 2004 & 2005.
- Member of CROMA (Crossing Republic Owners & Members Association) since 2013.

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 16 / 10 / 1983

Marital status: Married

Poonam Fojdar